<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Https on rmauro.dev {blog}</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/https/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Https on rmauro.dev {blog}</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 22:57:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/https/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Generating a Self-Signed Certificate using Powershell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/generating-a-self-signed-certificate-using-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 22:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/generating-a-self-signed-certificate-using-powershell/</guid>
      <description>A self-signed certificate it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to create and helps on with local development and testing.&#xA;With a Single Line of PowerShell code we create a certificate.&#xA;First, open the PowerShell as Administrator and run the following command:&#xA;New-SelfSignedCertificate ` –DnsName &amp;lt;DNS-Name&amp;gt; ` -CertStoreLocation &amp;#34;cert:\LocalMachine\My&amp;#34; The default expiration is 1 year. If you want a custom expiration date use option -NotAfter.&#xA;New-SelfSignedCertificate ` –DnsName &amp;lt;DNS-Name&amp;gt; ` -CertStoreLocation &amp;#34;cert:\LocalMachine\My&amp;#34; ` -NotAfter [System.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple Web Application with HTTP 2 over Kestrel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/enabling-http-2-on-kestrel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 22:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/enabling-http-2-on-kestrel/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post we&amp;rsquo;re going to create a simple web application with HTTP 2 enable on Kestrel.&#xA;Prerequisites to follow this article:&#xA;OpenSSL for Windows - to generate a self signed certificate First let generate a self signed SSL certificate. If you have an existing one you can skip this step.&#xA;On an existing .Net application open the Program.cs file.&#xA;public class Program { public static void Main(string[] args) { CreateHostBuilder(args).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure App Service and Cloudflare with Full SSL (Strict)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/azure-app-service-and-cloudflare-with-full-ssl-strict/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 23:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/azure-app-service-and-cloudflare-with-full-ssl-strict/</guid>
      <description>In this article we will set up Cloudflare as a reverse proxy and Azure Web Apps as a web service. Looking for the best security configuration that Cloudflare offers in the free tier.&#xA;At the end we will have the following configuration:&#xA;CloudFlare as reverse proxy Azure Web App as a web service Valid SSL (green lock) Full trust SSL between Cloudflare and Azure Web Apps (Cloudflare validating server side certificate) Application Domains / (A Name) and GHOST_URL/ (C Name) Our goal beyond valid SSL (green lock) is end-to-end encryption.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure App Service e Cloudflare com SSL Full (strict)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/azure-app-service-e-cloudflare-com-ssl-full-strict/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 20:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/azure-app-service-e-cloudflare-com-ssl-full-strict/</guid>
      <description>[english version]&#xA;Vamos configurar o Cloudflare como proxy reverso e Azure Web Apps como serviço de web. Buscando a melhor configuração de segurança que o Cloudflare oferece na camada gratuíta e cadeado verde.&#xA;Ao final teremos a seguinte configuração:&#xA;CloudFlare como proxy reverso Azure Web App como serviço web SSL válido (cadeado verde) SSL full trust entre Cloudflare e Azure Web Apps (Cloudflare validando certificado do lado do servidor) Domínios para aplicação / (A Name) e https://www.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HSTS - What&#39;s it and how to enable it in IIS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/hsts-definition-and-how-to-enable-it-in-iis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 18:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/hsts-definition-and-how-to-enable-it-in-iis/</guid>
      <description>###HSTS, what&amp;rsquo;s it?&#xA;Definition from wikipedia:&#xA;HTTP Strict Transport Security (HSTS) is a web security policy mechanism which helps to protect websites against protocol downgrade attacks and cookie hijacking. It allows web servers to declare that web browsers (or other complying user agents) should only interact with it using secure HTTPS connections,[1] and never via the insecure HTTP protocol. HSTS is an IETF standards track protocol and is specified in RFC 6797.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
