<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oracle on rmauro.dev {blog}</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/oracle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oracle on rmauro.dev {blog}</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 21:20:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/oracle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Remove Duplicate from Table</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-remove-duplicate-from-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 21:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-remove-duplicate-from-table/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s explore a one effective method to remove duplicate rows from an Oracle table.&#xA;Duplicate data can be a common problem when working with databases, and it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to eliminate such redundancy to ensure data accuracy and improve query performance.&#xA;Using this simple query we can find and DELETE duplicate rows from Oracle TABLE.&#xA;DELETE FROM your_table WHERE rowid NOT IN ( SELECT MIN(rowid) FROM your_table GROUP BY column1 , column2 , column3 ); This solution uses the GROUP BY clause, which clusters the records based on the uniqueness of specified columns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using dbms_stats to Gather Oracle Stats for Schema, Table and Indexes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/gather-oracle-stats-for-schema-tables-indexes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 19:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/gather-oracle-stats-for-schema-tables-indexes/</guid>
      <description>In the world of Oracle Database Management, gathering statistics plays a crucial role in optimizing query performance. Accurate statistics help the query optimizer make informed decisions about execution plans.&#xA;In this introduction let&amp;rsquo;s explore how to gather statistics for Schemas, Tables, and Indexes using Oracle simple commands.&#xA;Table of Contents Gather Schema Stats Gather Table Stats Gather Index Stats Gather Schema Stats with GATHER_SCHEMA_STATS To collect statistics for an entire schema, use the following command.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle ODP.NET with truly Async Methods in C#</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-odp-net-with-truly-async-methods-in-csharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 18:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-odp-net-with-truly-async-methods-in-csharp/</guid>
      <description>Oracle&amp;rsquo;s ODP.NET 23c Dev (or Oracle.ManagedDataAccess.Core) release brings genuine async/asynchronous methods to support to database interactions in C#, revolutionizing the way developers work with Oracle databases.&#xA;Under PreRelease until today : 2023-08-24&#xA;Oracle.ManagedDataAccess.Core - pre release&#xA;Async/Await in C# Before delving into the specifics of ODP.NET 23c Dev for C#, let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to understand the power of asynchronous programming in C#.&#xA;The async/await pattern enables developers to write non-blocking code, freeing the main thread to perform other tasks while asynchronous operations are in progress.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle PIVOT Command - Turn Rows into Columns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-pivot-command-turn-rows-into-columns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 23:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-pivot-command-turn-rows-into-columns/</guid>
      <description>Discover the technical prowess of Oracle&amp;rsquo;s PIVOT command, a robust feature that efficiently converts rows into columns.&#xA;This blog post delves into the syntax, use cases, and practical examples to illustrate how PIVOT simplifies data analysis and reporting in Oracle databases.&#xA;Understanding the PIVOT Command The PIVOT command is an extension of the SQL SELECT statement in Oracle. It lets you rotate rows into columns, effectively transposing data to achieve a more structured and readable output.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle JSON_TABLE Transforming JSON into Table</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-json-table-transforming-json-into-relational-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 17:35:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-json-table-transforming-json-into-relational-format/</guid>
      <description>The function JSON_TABLE allows us to transform JSON data into a table relational format.&#xA;This article will explore the Oracle JSON_TABLE function and its syntax and provide examples to demonstrate its usage and capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle MERGE Statement SQL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-merge-to-update-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 18:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-merge-to-update-sql/</guid>
      <description>Oracle MERGE statement is one of those powerful commands which allows you to perform INSERT and UPDATE operations in a single statement based on specific conditions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Query Performance on C# ODP.NET - Oracle Managed Data Access</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/optmizing-data-access-with-oracle-managed-ado-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 14:38:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/optmizing-data-access-with-oracle-managed-ado-net/</guid>
      <description>Oracle C# drive is already pretty fast with the default configuration. But we can always tweak it a little to make it even faster. By controlling the FetchSize property in ODP.NET we can make fewer round trips to Oracle Database and fetch the data faster.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at how it&amp;rsquo;s done and make your data access faster.&#xA;Setup the Environment Before we get started let&amp;rsquo;s set up our environment for testing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Database on Docker for Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-database-on-docker-for-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 17:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-database-on-docker-for-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lets set up an Oracle Database instance for development purpose using Docker is very easy. And it also runs in WSL2 over Windows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s use the oracleinanutshell/oracle-xe-11g image.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
