<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sql on rmauro.dev {blog}</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sql on rmauro.dev {blog}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.130.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 21:20:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Remove Duplicate from Table</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-remove-duplicate-from-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 21:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-remove-duplicate-from-table/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s explore a one effective method to remove duplicate rows from an Oracle table.
Duplicate data can be a common problem when working with databases, and it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to eliminate such redundancy to ensure data accuracy and improve query performance.
Using this simple query we can find and DELETE duplicate rows from Oracle TABLE.
DELETE FROM your_table WHERE rowid NOT IN ( SELECT MIN(rowid) FROM your_table GROUP BY column1 , column2 , column3 ); This solution uses the GROUP BY clause, which clusters the records based on the uniqueness of specified columns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle PIVOT Command - Turn Rows into Columns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-pivot-command-turn-rows-into-columns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 23:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-pivot-command-turn-rows-into-columns/</guid>
      <description>Discover the technical prowess of Oracle&amp;rsquo;s PIVOT command, a robust feature that efficiently converts rows into columns.
This blog post delves into the syntax, use cases, and practical examples to illustrate how PIVOT simplifies data analysis and reporting in Oracle databases.
Understanding the PIVOT Command The PIVOT command is an extension of the SQL SELECT statement in Oracle. It lets you rotate rows into columns, effectively transposing data to achieve a more structured and readable output.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle JSON_TABLE Transforming JSON into Table</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-json-table-transforming-json-into-relational-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 17:35:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-json-table-transforming-json-into-relational-format/</guid>
      <description>The function JSON_TABLE allows us to transform JSON data into a table relational format.
This article will explore the Oracle JSON_TABLE function and its syntax and provide examples to demonstrate its usage and capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle MERGE Statement SQL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-merge-to-update-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 18:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/oracle-merge-to-update-sql/</guid>
      <description>Oracle MERGE statement is one of those powerful commands which allows you to perform INSERT and UPDATE operations in a single statement based on specific conditions.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
