<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>White-Hat on rmauro.dev {blog}</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/white-hat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in White-Hat on rmauro.dev {blog}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.130.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 06:16:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/white-hat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Slowloris Attack #whitehat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/slow-loris-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 06:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/slow-loris-attack/</guid>
      <description>Denial-of-Service (DoS) attacks are a critical threat to web server security. One particularly insidious type is the Slowloris attack, which can incapacitate a server with minimal resources.
Remember, this guide is for educational purposes only, and any unauthorized testing on live servers is illegal and unethical.
What is a Slow Loris Attack? A Slow Loris attack involves sending numerous incomplete HTTP requests to a target server.
By maintaining these connections open with periodic headers but never completing them, the server&amp;rsquo;s resources are tied up, preventing legitimate users from accessing the server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL Injection with SQLMap #whitehat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/sql-injection-with-sqlmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 23:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/sql-injection-with-sqlmap/</guid>
      <description>SQLMap is a powerful and popular open-source tool used to detect and exploit SQL injection vulnerabilities.
Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into a basic usage of SQLMap.
Pre-Requirements Linux Installation sudo apt-get install sqlmap Windows Installation Download and install from SQLMap from the official website SQL Map
Basic Usage In the terminal or command prompt. Run SQLMap with a target URL that is suspected of being vulnerable to SQL injection:
sqlmap -u &amp;#34;http://example.com/page?id=1&amp;#34; Basic Options -u URL, --url=URL: Specifies the URL to test.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
